[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"1. People of this ethnicity were granted a monopoly on trade with Venezuela by the Bourbon Reforms. This ethnic group’s whalers spoke an Algonquian pidgin language and were subjected to a 1615 massacre in Iceland. Terrorists of this ethnicity participated in 1973’s Operation Ogre, which resulted in the carbombing of Luis Carrero Blanco. The Song of Roland records how an army of this ethnicity ambushed Charlemagne at Roncevaux Pass. The 2004 Madrid train bombings were initially blamed on this ethnicity’s ETA terrorist group. For 10 points, name this Iberian ethnic minority whose namesake “country” straddles France and Spain. ","answer":"ANSWER: Basques [or Vascos; or Euskaldunak] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"2. This author’s name is used in place of the phrase “excuse me” in Derek Walcott’s Ti-Jean and his Brothers. This writer isn’t American, but his work inspired a play broken into the sections The Homecoming, The Hunted, and The Haunted. Christine poisons her Civil War general husband Ezra Mannon in that Eugene O’Neill work based on one of this author’s plays. Prometheus Bound is a sequel to one of his plays, and his work inspired the modern adaptations Mourning Becomes Electra and Jean Paul Sartre’s The Flies. During a fictional poetry contest in Aristophanes’s The Frogs, this playwright beats Euripides. For 10 points, name this Greek tragedian and playwright of the Oresteia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aeschylus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"3. These functional groups are synthesized from nitriles using tin(II) [tin two] chloride in the Stephen synthesis. The simplest aromatic example of these functional groups is the active flavorant in almond extract. In hydrogen NMR, compounds with these functional groups show a peak from 9-10 ppm. PCC can convert primary alcohols to these functional groups. These functional groups, which cause a magenta color change in the Schiff test, form a characteristic “silver mirror” when using Tollens’ reagent. For ten points, name these functional groups that contain a terminal carbon double bonded to an oxygen, unlike ketones. ","answer":"ANSWER: aldehydes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"4. Parashurama killed Kartavirya Arjuna after Arjuna stole one of these animals from Parashurama’s father, the sage Jamadagni. Prithu received vegetation and grain from one of these animals named Prithvi. According to the Mahabharata, the Saptarishi received one of these animals named Kamadhenu that emerged from the churning of the ocean. Shiva’s mount, Nandi, is one of these animals. The final abode of Krishna is sometimes referred to as the “heaven” of these animals, which Krishna herded as a boy. For 10 points, name these animals which Hindus consider sacred and avoid eating. ","answer":"ANSWER: cows [or cattle; or bulls] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"5. A philosophical text written in this language argues against the belief that fire burns cotton, instead declaring that cotton is burned by God. Followers of a philosopher who wrote in this language argued for the possible coexistence of differing philosophical and religious truths, a doctrine referred to as “double truth.” A text in this language denounces 20 heretic views stated by other philosophers, such as the pre-eternity of the world and ordinary causality. The Incoherence of the Philosophers and The Incoherence of the Incoherence were written in this language, which was also used to write commentaries on Aristotle by Averroes. For 10 points, name this language used by the Muslim philosopher al-Ghazali. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arabic "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"6. A member of this minority group attempted to kidnap the royal family in the Surprise of Meaux. Poorly-disciplined dragoons were forcibly billeted in this group’s homes under the Dragonnades policy. Members of this group put posters on the door of the king’s bedchamber in the Affair of the Placards. The Duke of Buckingham helped defend these people at the Siege of La Rochelle. This group’s admiral Gaspard de Coligny was murdered during a massacre ordered by Catherine de’ Medici on St. Bartholomew’s Day. For 10 points, the Edict of Nantes granted religious freedom to what group of French Protestants? ","answer":"ANSWER: Huguenots [or French Protestants until it is read; prompt on Protestants or Calvinists] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"7. At the end of one of this author’s plays, the Mayor turns to the audience to say “What are you laughing about? You are laughing about yourselves!” In that play by this author, Khlestakov cons a village into believing he is an incognito government official. One of this author’s novels ends mid-sentence as a prince lambasts Chichikov for purchasing the property of dead peasants. The Person of Importance is robbed by a ghost at the end of this author’s story about the copy clerk Akaky Akakievich. For 10 points, name this Russian author of Dead Souls and “The Overcoat.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Nikolai Gogol "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"8. This effect can cause spacecraft to build up a positive charge on the side facing the Sun through surface charging. This effect was first observed by Heinrich Hertz when using a coil and a spark gap. Robert Millikan confirmed this effect in an experiment in which he verified the value of Planck’s constant. Maxwell’s electromagnetism incorrectly predicted that in this effect, the electron energy would be proportional to the intensity of the incoming radiation. A 1905 paper explaining how this effect is due to quantized light won Albert Einstein won a Nobel Prize. For 10 points, name this effect, the emission of electrons when light shines on a material. ","answer":"ANSWER: photoelectric effect [prompt on surface charging until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"9. The second movement of this composition opens with a solo horn playing the slow notes (read slowly) long F, G, A-flat, long B-flat. At the beginning of this suite, col legno strings play a unison G in a rhythm consisting of triplet eighth-notes, two quarter notes, two eighth notes, and a quarter note. This suite’s final movement creates a “fade-out” effect by closing the door on an offstage women’s chorus. The hymn “I Vow to Thee, My Country” was set to the melody of one of this suite’s movements, which is subtitled “the Bringer of Jollity.” For 10 points, name this Gustav Holst suite with movements named “Mars” and “Jupiter.” ","answer":"ANSWER: The Planets "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"0. Greater government spending does not increase demand because consumers expect an increase in this variable, according to the Ricardian equivalence model. Frank Ramsey inspired Peter Diamond and James Mirrlees to research the “optimal” value for this variable to maximize social welfare. The price elasticity of demand can help determine the “incidence” of these things, which are supported by the “benefit principle.” Externalities can be internalized using a policy of this type designed by Arthur Pigou. Examples of these things include excises and tariffs. For 10 points, name these economic policies that governments use to raise revenue. ","answer":"ANSWER: taxation [or tax rate; or tax revenue; or word forms; prompt on specific types of taxes like tariff or excise] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"1. This event began in response to the issue of sixty subpoenas by William Rawle, which was argued to be a deliberate provocation by Congressman William Findley. The anonymous “Tom the Tinker” and the Mingo Creek Association threatened enemies of this event like John Neville, whose house at Bower Hill was the focus of its first shots. “Light-Horse Harry” Lee led the troops that put down this uprising. The derisively nicknamed “Watermelon Army” participated in this rebellion to protest a financial measure implemented by Alexander Hamilton. For 10 points, name this Pennsylvania frontier revolt caused by a tax an alcohol. ","answer":"ANSWER: Whiskey Rebellion [or the Whiskey Revolt; or the Whiskey Uprising] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"2. The first sentence of this novel describes a woman whose beauty “seems to be thrown into relief by poor dress.” A landlord in this novel asks Mary Garth to destroy his will in order to deprive Joshua Rigg of his inheritance. One of this novel’s characters spends his honeymoon studying books in the Vatican library. That character in this novel is treated by Rosamond Vincy’s husband, Tertius Lydgate, and dies without finishing his book The Key to All Mythologies. In this novel, Edward Casaubon leaves a will stipulating that Will Ladislaw cannot marry Dorothea Brooke. For 10 points, name this “study of provincial life” by George Eliot. ","answer":"ANSWER: Middlemarch: A Study of Provincial Life "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"3. This pathway shares intermediates like sedulose-1,7-bisphosphate and xylulose-5-phosphate with the pentose phosphate pathway. An exciton forms at the special pair in the first phase of this process before the lone electron is shuttled from pheophytin to plastoquinone. To make up for how inefficiently it turns over, an enzyme in this pathway is the most common protein on Earth. NADP carries electrons in this pathway away from the P680 and P700 complexes. The thylakoid lumen develops a pH gradient during the light-dependent phase of this process. For 10 points, name this pathway that fixes carbon in the Calvin cycle and is used by plants to harvest solar energy. ","answer":"ANSWER: photosynthesis [or light-dependent reactions or LDR until it is read; or Calvin cycle until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"4. In 1845, John Snare allegedly found a lost painting by this artist depicting Charles I. This artist assisted Peter Paul Rubens in making a copy of Titian’s Rape of Europa, a painting he later featured as a tapestry in the background of a work depicting The Fable of Arachne. This artist’s still-life of a woman frying eggs is in the bodegón (bow-de-GON) genre. He made a portrait of the freed slave Juan de Pareja. This artist stands behind an easel wearing the red cross of the Order of Santiago in his most famous painting, which depicts two dwarves and a dog around the Infanta Margaret Theresa. For 10 points, name this Spanish Golden Age painter of Las Meninas. ","answer":"ANSWER: Diego Velázquez "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"5. Lanterns called fanous are often hung during this time period. According to one text, a night that takes place during this period is “better than a thousand months.” Because that night during this period can take place on any of five days, many adherents choose to practice i’tikah for ten days. During this period, daybreak is defined as the moment when a white thread appears distinct from a black thread. Extra prayers called tarawih are said during this period, during which adherents of a certain religion observe sawm. This month ends with the feast of Eid al-Fitr. For 10 points, name this month of the Islamic calendar in which Muslims fast from dawn to dusk. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ramadan [prompt on specific parts of Ramadan like Laylat al-Qadr and Eid al-Fitr] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"6. This leader wrote the Greek phrase “ginesthoi,” or “make it happen!” at the bottom of a document granting tax exemptions to Quintus Caecilius. Blaise Pascal claimed that “the world would have been changed” if this leader had a shorter nose. Despite a grant of sanctuary, this leader had her sister Arsinoe killed on the steps of the Temple of Artemis. The Donations of Alexandria distributed royal titles to this leader’s children, including her son Caesarion. After the Battle of Actium, this member of the Ptolemaic dynasty committed suicide with an asp. For 10 points, name this lover of Mark Antony and Julius Caesar who ruled as Queen of Egypt. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cleopatra VII Philopator "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"7. A newspaper based in this state won a Pulitzer Prize for its “Seven Days of Heroin” project. Macedonian immigrants to this state developed a type of chili that is poured over spaghetti noodles and garnished with oyster crackers. In 2011, 56 exotic animals escaped from a private zoo in this state’s town of Zanesville. Goodyear Tires is based in this state in a city that is nicknamed the “Rubber Capital of the World.” The Cuyahoga River flows through this state, where the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame is located on the shores of Lake Erie. For 10 points, name this US state, home to cities like Akron, Cincinnati, and Cleveland. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ohio "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"8. The speaker of a jazz standard set in this city owns a “cozy little flat,” in which she’ll “settle down / right here in town.” A bandleader from this city invited audiences to sing “hi-dee-hi-dee-hi-dee-hi” in the scat chorus of his song “Minnie the Moocher.” Paul Whiteman pioneered symphonic jazz in this city, which is where Cab Calloway led the house band of a whites-only nightclub. Billy Strayhorn composed “Take the ‘A’ Train” for a bandleader associated with this city’s Cotton Club, Duke Ellington. For 10 points, name this city where jazz flourished during the Harlem Renaissance. ","answer":"ANSWER: New York City [or NYC; prompt on Manhattan; prompt on Harlem until mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"9. One mathematician from this country lends his name to a theorem stating that every group G is isomorphic to a subgroup of the symmetric group acting on G. A mathematician from this country used his proof of the Taniyama-Shimura conjecture for semistable elliptic curves to find a proof for Fermat’s last theorem. This country was also home to a mathematician who developed a namesake “method” to approximate the roots of a function by repeatedly taking derivatives. That mathematician argued with Gottlieb Leibniz over who developed calculus. For 10 points, name this country home to Arthur Cayley, Andrew Wiles, and Isaac Newton. ","answer":"ANSWER: United Kingdom [or Britain; or England] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"0. A poem set in this city describes “parking spaces” that “luxuriate like civic sandpiles.” One of this city’s characteristic “marriages” is exemplified by Olive Chancellor’s relationship with Verena Tarrant in an 1886 novel. Another novel notes that the “forefathers” of this city chose to build a cemetery and a prison before anything else. A “savage servility slides by on grease” through this city, which “stands in a Sahara of snow” according to Robert Lowell’s poem “For the Union Dead.” This city, whose residents title a Henry James novel, is largely the setting of The Scarlet Letter. For 10 points, name this city, whose literary “Brahmins” often lectured at Harvard College. ","answer":"ANSWER: Boston [accept The Bostonians; prompt on Cambridge] Tiebreaker. The carbon in pulp process describes the recovery of this element. The Elsner equation describes the dissolution of this element through a cyanide solution. The relativistic contraction of this element’s 5s orbitals give it its characteristic color, and that of its 6s orbitals contribute to its resistance to corrosion. Complexes of this element can exhibit aurophilicity. The scattering of alpha particles on this element’s nuclei was observed by Geiger and Marsden, who used a foil made of this element. Aqua regia can dissolve both this element and platinum. Pyrite is sometimes nicknamed the “fool’s” type of this element. For 10 points, name this precious metal with a yellowish color. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Fine’s book Shared Fantasy discusses this leisure activity, which Philip Zimbardo linked to the “failure” of boys in his book Man, Interrupted. It doesn’t involve movies or music, but many studies have examined the relation between this leisure activity and males’ desensitization to violence. ","answer":"ANSWER: playing video games [or gaming; accept any descriptive or specific answers that involve video games] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Fine defines “naturework” as the way we give meaning to our surroundings in a book about people who collect these organisms. This organism appears in the title of an Anna Tsing book about “the Possibility of Life in Capitalist Ruins.” ","answer":"ANSWER: mushrooms [or Morel Tales: The Culture of Mushrooming; or The Mushroom at the End of the World: On the Possibility of Life in Capitalist Ruins; prompt on fungi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Fine’s book Sticky Reputations examines the influence of the “collective” form of this concept advanced by Maurice Halbwachs. This term refers to our ability to store and retrieve information. ","answer":"ANSWER: memory "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this law, which states that “2 d sine theta equals n lambda” to give the scattering angles of light diffraction in a crystal lattice. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bragg’s law "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Bragg’s law describes the diffraction of light rays in this region of the electromagnetic spectrum. These rays, first discovered by William Röntgen, are commonly used to image bones. ","answer":"ANSWER: X-rays [or X-radiation] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This German scientist received the 1914 Nobel Prize in Physics for discovering X-ray diffraction, predating the work of the Braggs. X-ray diffraction is sometimes known as a type of diffraction named for this man. ","answer":"ANSWER: Max von Laue "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this snake-like giant who, along with Echidna, is the father of many of Greece’s most famous monsters. ","answer":"ANSWER: Typhon [or Typhos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This offspring of Typhon had poisonous breath and blood so toxic that even smelling it could kill you. Heracles had to burn this monster’s necks in order to stop its many heads from regenerating. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lernaean Hydra [or Hydra of Lerna] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This two-headed dog was the first child of Typhon and Echidna. He was charged with guarding Geryon’s cattle and was eventually killed by Heracles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Orthrus [or Orthus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this algorithm extended by the Bellman-Ford algorithm, which allows for negative edge weights. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dijkstra’s algorithm "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Dijkstra’s algorithm is used to find shortest paths in these mathematical collections of vertices and edges. The Seven Bridges of Königsberg problem laid the foundation for the “theory” of these structures. ","answer":"ANSWER: graphs [or graph theory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The priority queues often used to store edges in Dijkstra’s algorithm can be implemented with the “min” variety of this tree-based data structure, in which each node’s leaves are less than or equal to the node itself. ","answer":"ANSWER: heap [or min heap; or binary heap] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this Holy Roman Emperor who called the Diet of Roncaglia after subduing Milan. This red-bearded commander drowned fording the Saleph River during the Third Crusade. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frederick Barbarossa [or Frederick I] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Frederick’s authority in Italy was opposed by this alliance of cities backed by Pope Alexander III. This alliance shared its name with a people once ruled by Desiderius. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lombard League "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The Lombard League shattered Frederick’s army at this 1176 battle, ending his dream of direct imperial rule in Italy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Battle of Legnano "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this First Lady whose chic greatly influenced the trends of Western fashion in the 1960s and 70s. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jacqueline “Jackie” Kennedy [or Jacqueline Bouvier; or Jacqueline Onassis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Kennedy often wore a strapless gown of this color designed by Christian Dior. On the day of her husband’s assassination, Kennedy was wearing an iconic Chanel wool suit of this color that became stained with blood. ","answer":"ANSWER: pink [or strawberry pink] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Ann Lowe, one of the first prominent African-American fashion designers, designed a famed one of these clothing items for Kennedy using ivory silk taffeta. In 2011, Sarah Burton designed one of these clothing items for Kate Middleton. ","answer":"ANSWER: wedding dress [or bridal gown; accept equivalents; prompt on dress] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this poetic title character who lived in a “pretty how town.” “Women and men” both “little and small” don’t care for this character, whose life is the subject of a poem with the refrain “sun moon stars rain.” ","answer":"ANSWER: anyone [or “anyone lived in a pretty how town”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This capitalization-adverse poet wrote “anyone lived in a pretty how town.” A “conscientious object-or” whose “warmest heart recoiled at war” appears in his poem “i sing of Olaf glad and big.” ","answer":"ANSWER: e. e. cummings [or Edward Estlin Cummings] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This Imagist writer bet mutual friend Scofield Thayer that cummings would not be a successful poet. The speaker of her poem “Patterns” observes “squills and daffodils” before exclaiming “Christ! What are patterns for?” ","answer":"ANSWER: Amy Lowell [prompt on Lowell] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this country where Ronald Reagan and Mikhail Gorbachev met for a 1986 summit. In 1949, protesters attacked this country’s parliament, the Althing, after it voted to join NATO. ","answer":"ANSWER: Iceland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] During the Cold War, NATO used Iceland as a base to monitor the activity of these Soviet warships, which could be used to store missiles. The “nuclear” variety of these submersible vessels is powered by a nuclear reactor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Soviet nuclear submarines [or ballistic missile submarines; prompt on subs] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The Althing repeatedly threatened to leave NATO during this series of informal conflicts between Iceland and the United Kingdom. This “war” ended when Britain agreed to stop harassing Icelandic fishing ships. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Cod Wars "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Plasma and memory cells are both involved in the “adaptive” form of what system, which is contrasted with its “innate” form? ","answer":"ANSWER: immune system [or innate immune system; or adaptive immune system] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Plasma cells are examples of these white blood cells that secrete antibodies. These lymphocytes are contrasted with natural killer cells and T cells. ","answer":"ANSWER: B cells [or B lymphocytes; accept plasma B cells; prompt on lymphocytes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] B cells are activated by the type 1 and 2 of these immune system signaling molecules. These cytokines were once thought to be exclusively used as communication between white blood cells. ","answer":"ANSWER: interleukins [or ILs; or IL-1; or IL-2] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this composer of a piece for an indefinite amount of performers consisting of 53 short numbered musical phrases, each intended to be repeated an arbitrary number of times independently by each musician. That piece by this composer is called In C. ","answer":"ANSWER: Terry Riley "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Terry Riley is a composer from this musical movement. Other composers associated with this movement include the composer of Dif erent Trains, Steve Reich, and Nixon and China composer John Adams. ","answer":"ANSWER: minimalism [accept word forms; prompt on modernism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Terry Riley, Steve Reich, and John Adams are all minimalist composers from this country. ","answer":"ANSWER: United States of America [or America] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Identify this concept which, according to that text, is a “blind striving.” A posthumous text by a different philosopher declares that the world is this thing “and nothing besides!” ","answer":"ANSWER: will [accept Will-to-Life or Will-to-Live or Wille zum Leben; accept Will to Power or Wille zur Macht] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This German pessimist used the philosophy of the Upanishads to state that human life should focus on opposing the Will-to-Life via asceticism in his book The World as Will and Representation. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arthur Schopenhauer "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This German nihilist philosopher declared that “the world is the will to power – and nothing besides!” This author of Beyond Good and Evil coined the term “will to power” in Thus Spoke Zarathustra. ","answer":"ANSWER: Friedrich (Wilhelm) Nietzsche "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"4. After World War II, Niemoller apologized for his previous support of this leader’s anti-Semitic policies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Adolf Hitler "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Anti-Nazi theologians like Dietrich Bonhoeffer and Karl Barth formed this Christian movement after the Nazi Party officially absorbed Germany’s Protestant church. This movement’s views were expressed in the Barmen Declaration. ","answer":"ANSWER” the Confessing Church [or Bekennende Kirche] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s The Cost of Discipleship is an extended analysis of this Biblical event. This New Testament event is the source of the expressions “salt of the earth” and “turn the other cheek.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the Sermon on the Mount [prompt on the Beatitudes; prompt on the Gospel of Matthew] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this member of the Angry Young Men. The medieval history professor Jim Dixon is fired at the end of his campus novel Lucky Jim. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kingsley Amis [prompt on just Amis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Alan Sillitoe, another member of the Angry Young Men, is most famous for this short story, in which Smith loses a race on purpose to spite his school. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In Lucky Jim, Jim Dixon gives a drunken lecture about this “merrie” place. Amis, Sillitoe, and other members of the Angry Young Men set much of their work in this country.. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Merrie England” [accept Great Britain or the United Kingdom] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this empire known to the Han as “Daqin.” Emperor Huan of Han received ambassadors from this empire who claimed to have been sent by Marcus Aurelius. ","answer":"ANSWER: Roman Empire [or Rome] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The Han were more successful in taking control of this modern-day country, which briefly secured independence from China during the Trung Sisters’ rebellion. This country’s last emperor, Bao Dai, ruled from the imperial city of Hue (he-WAY). ","answer":"ANSWER: Vietnam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Emperor Wu of Han fought to acquire “heavenly” horses from the Dayuan of the Ferghana Valley in order to deploy them against these northern barbarians, whose incursions led to the construction of the Great Wall. ","answer":"ANSWER: Xiongnu [prompt on Huns] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this molecule, the simplest ketone. It is used in nail polish remover. ","answer":"ANSWER: acetone "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Most acetone is often industrially produced along with phenol in this process. This process, which was discovered by Heinrich Hock, is named for an aromatic intermediate. ","answer":"ANSWER: cumene-phenol process "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Cumene is produced by substituting a hydrogen on this molecule with an isopropyl group. Phenol is made by adding a hydroxyl group to this aromatic molecule, which has formula C6H6 . ","answer":"ANSWER: benzene "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this profession. In “The Albatross,” this profession is compared to a “prince of cloud and sky” whose “giant wings prevent him from walking.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the poet [prompt on writer or author] [10] “Benediction” and “The Albatross” appear in The Flowers of Evil alongside “The Swan,” which reflects on this city’s modernization. The second section of The Flowers of Evil is titled for this city’s “scenes.” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This writer reflected on the role of the poet, as well as the modernization of Paris, throughout his Symbolist masterpiece The Flowers of Evil. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles Baudelaire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name these works that were traditionally printed on vellum, a prepared animal skin. The Book of Kells is a well-known example of this type of work. ","answer":"ANSWER: illuminated manuscripts [prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Prehistoric artists often preserved animal skins using a variety of the pigment ochre that was this color. Vermillion was another popular pigment of this color. ","answer":"ANSWER: red "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Native American artists began creating “ledger art” after it became difficult to obtain the hides of these animals, which were the most common hides used by Plains Indians to make teepees. One of these ungulates appears in the Wyoming state flag. ","answer":"ANSWER: American bison [or buffalo; accept buffalo hides; or bison hides] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this deliverer of the “Solitude of Self” speech who lost much of her influence after the publication of The Women’s Bible. ","answer":"ANSWER: Elizabeth Cady Stanton "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Stanton added a resolution advancing this cause to the Declaration of Sentiments at the Seneca Falls Convention. The aim of this cause was achieved with the passage of the 19th Amendment. ","answer":"ANSWER: women’s suffrage [accept women receiving the vote or equivalents; prompt on suffrage] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Stanton’s shift on Black civil rights was criticised by this man, who argued that Black men deserved the vote before White women. Earlier, this man was the only African American attendee at the Seneca Falls Conference. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frederick Douglass "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: Whitney Houston "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Houston’s family criticized Pusha T for using a photograph of Houston’s bathroom after her death as the cover art for this 2018 album. Its tracks include “If You Know You Know” and an epic takedown of Meek Mill, “What Would Meek Do?” ","answer":"ANSWER: Daytona "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This rapper, who produced Pusha T’s Daytona, personally shelled out $85,000 to acquire the rights to the photograph of Houston’s bathroom. This husband of Kim Kardashian recently visited President Trump at the White House. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kanye West [accept either underlined portion; also accept Yeezy or Ye] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this capital city. Palace Walk is the first work in a trilogy of novels set in this city by the author of Midaq Alley. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cairo [accept the Cairo Trilogy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Egyptian author Naguib Mahfouz, who wrote the Cairo Trilogy, is the only author to have received the Nobel Prize in Literature for writing primarily in this language. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arabic "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This British novelist wrote a Quartet of novels set in Egypt’s city of Alexandria. His brother Gerald wrote My Family and Other Animals, which chronicles this author’s eccentric upbringing in Corfu. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lawrence Durrell Tiebreaker. The Taft-Katsura memorandum acknowledged Japan’s stake in Korea and disinterest in this country. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"6. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Philippines "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This leader of the Philippine Senate led a 1934 delegation to Washington, D.C. to secure independence. It’s not Manila, but the Philippines’ largest city is named for this first president of the Commonwealth of the Philippines. ","answer":"ANSWER: Manuel Quezon [or Quezon City] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This earlier leader of the Filipino independence movement led a guerilla campaign against Spain towards the end of its occupation of the Philippines. Once the Spanish left, he continued his war against the United States until he was captured by Frederick Funston. ","answer":"ANSWER: Emilio Aguinaldo"}]
